how's it going everyone this is Nick at
bobbed.com and today I'm walking you
through our picks for the best
multivitamins for women so we're going
to be walking you through the
ingredients how we landed on these picks
what you should be emphasizing in your
own nutrition when you're looking for
supplements like this so you can decide
which is right for you and your own
individual lifestyle I should make it
clear here this is my disclaimer I'm not
a doctor I'm not a medical professional
if you're making any changes to your
diet and exercise regimen I strongly
encourage you to speak to a qualified
medical professional like your GP or at
least a registered dietitian to make
sure you're doing the Right Moves for
your own lifestyle medications you might
be taking stuff like that now to start
off you probably just want to know right
now what the best pick is and I'll tell
you that's okay I respect your time it's
Wolverine it's got a really broad
variety of nutrients here and we also
really like that it has ingredients that
emphasized hydration as well which is a
nice extra touch that a lot of
multivitamins don't include before we
keep going deeper into when all the
reasons why we landed on Sovereign and
the other picks here a quick worried
about multivitamins they are not
mentally replacing fruits and vegetables
right a better way to look at
multivitamins is as a way to supplement
your diet as opposed to being the
backbone of it right so still eating
veggies still eat plenty of protein and
carbohydrates and fats what this does is
they help to fill in gaps that you might
be making that might be appearing in
your diet unintentionally there are
plenty of ingredients like magnesium for
example which is hard to get unless
you're getting a lot of leafy greens
every day and a lot of legumes or
choline which is like really hard to
find outside of eggs so it's a good idea
for most people to have multivitamin
just a little bit of insurance there
[Music]
a question you might be asking is why
would we talk about women's
multivitamins like are there any
nutrients that women actually need more
of than men uh it's a good question
broadly speaking they're like the
recommended daily intake for a lot of
nutrients is largely the same for men
and women it's just that men are often
are told to get a little bit more of
them because they tend to weigh more
they can be a bit bigger so they tend to
need a bit more of certain nutrients
that said either are some nutrients that
a lot of experts recommend women focus a
bit more on than men a good example is
calcium women are at a high risk
osteoporosis as they age another one
that's important to get is for both men
and women is vitamin D men often talk
about vitamin D a lot because there's
some interesting links with hormone
production like testosterone that
doesn't mean the women shouldn't take it
at all it's about keeping your hormone
production like healthy and normal but
also vitamin D has very strong links to
Bone strength and again like burn health
and Bone strength that's very often
emphasized in women's supplements
because again there's a there's a higher
risk of a burn than degradation with
eight in addition to that there are some
nutrients that women tend to want more
of so there are ones that women are
advised to have more of and there's ones
that women have to take initiatives
themselves to look for very good example
there's biotin bison is a it's a vitamin
or it's a vitamin like substance there
are like different ways of classifying
biotin but you may already know this it
has some interesting links with uh
healthier hair stronger nails a
healthier skin like more skin elasticity
things like that same goes for collagen
so those are also ingredients that are
often found more in women's
multivitamins another interesting
difference between men's and women's
multivitamins is iron now because most
women menstruate menstruating women they
lose more iron than men do so they're
often advised to keep an eye on their
iron intake there are indeed a variety
of nutrients that are different between
men's and women's supplements that's why
you thought it'd be a good idea to make
a dedicated video for women's
multivitamins so let's talk about the
top pick Wolverine was our favorite one
for women this does have a very good
amount of ace
vitamins in addition to that it has more
than 100 video intake of biotin which as
I mentioned is often covered by female
consumers in addition to that it also
has a lot of interesting ingredients for
hydration like electrolytes like you
might have already heard of sodium as a
electrolyte but there's also a magnesium
phosphorus calcium these are also
electrolytes they're also all Kia in
good amounts and they will help to
hydrate as well so that makes it a good
choice especially for people who are
exercising regularly or if it's just
kind of hot out there you know getting
as hydrated as you want to be of the
ingredients here you get 16 of the
micronutrients here have 100 or more of
your recommended daily intake that's
really nice touch and it's fairly
inexpensive as well at about 66 cents
per day we also named this the best
Women's Multivitamin with iron I already
mentioned why iron can be of extra
importance for female consumers this has
150 of your daily intake of iron so easy
peasy whether you have plenty of meat in
your diet or even if you have no meat
whatsoever in your diet the iron content
here should help to keep you well and
truly topped up for this also it's got
plenty of B vitamins as well a lot of of
people may not know that B vitamins they
are very certainly linked to energy
production as well as like a mental
Clarity and focus that sort of thing I
should probably make it clear that it's
really more that if you're deficient in
these vitamins you'll experience they
benefit with more energy production if
this is able to bring you to a proper
healthy intake as opposed to taking 500
of the recommended intake is going to
make you really super energized
throughout the day so it is definitely a
good idea to have a multivitamin with a
whole Suite of B vitamins in it there
are plenty of athletes and bodybuilders
who purposely take extra B vitamin
supplements throughout the day so
they're having hundreds of percent will
recommended intake it's not something
you need to be really worried about of
having more than 100 of the intake so
definitely a multivitamin with extra B
vitamins is a pretty good bet for
athletes and also just for the average
everyday person because we vitamins
they're uh they're pretty damn good for
you and it's a good idea to have them in
space so Wolverine is our best overall
for women it's also our best with iron
and if you can believe it it is the best
value one as well it's our best cheap
multivitamin it's just 36 cents per day
so it's a really good buy overall to be
honest the cattle is here at gelatin
which are cheaper than the vegetarian
capsules you'll sometimes find on these
multivitamins so if you are a vegetarian
or if uh perhaps you eat like kosher or
Halal or something like that I don't
think this is going to be right for you
but those gels and capsules do help to
keep the price down it's not the only
thing but it is a factory that is
cheaper than the vegetarian capsules not
friendly to vegetarians but very very
good value at 66 cents per day so yeah
this is the best cheap multivitamin as
well if you can believe it next up we
want to talk about one of our favorite
Brands called transparent Labs we're
doing this one the best daily
multivitamin because it is very
transparent for wine like they're really
good at having the precise dosages of
all of their ingredients which is a real
part of the philosophy of this brand
there are 11 of the 19 ingredients here
that have over 100 of the recommended
daily intake and what's also cool is
they have some ingredients that are not
often included in multivitamins because
they're not like technically vitamins or
minerals but they still have helpful
effects there are a lot of ingredients
like that in the world like a lot of
antioxidants and phytonutrients that
sort of stuff what transparent Labs is
included here is some Boron which may be
useful for like a healthy hormone
production there's also got some CoQ10
which has some links with heart health
and some organic ashwagandha extract
that one's really cool you might have
heard of ashwagandha before it's an
adaptogen so what that means is it's
something that appears to help the body
to manage stress we named it our best
daily multivitamin but we also think
this is the best one for athletes too we
did mention that slaughtering has some
interesting compounds that are linked to
hydration what's really cool about uh
this one here from transparent Labs is
that in addition to that it also has
plenty of magnesium which is really
really important for athletes it's like
linked to recovery like so it's really
important for Sleep Quality and helping
to reduce stress in the body reduce
tension that sort of stuff it's often
called the relaxation nutrient and
there's a pretty impressive 70 of the
recommended daily intake in four of
these daily capsules so that's really
really cool in addition to that the
ashwagandha has pretty interesting links
to workout recovery as well and also
bone health for a lot of people and not
just women bone health is an important
component of why they exercise in the
first place right athletes in addition
to wanting stronger bones they also kind
of need stronger bones they're going to
be regularly lifting weights or engaging
in resistance training and this is a
really good overall approach to bone
health like it has calcium yes but also
has vitamin K which helps to deposit the
calcium on the bone to set up in the
arteries where you don't really want it
it's also got vitamin D with strong
links to bone health as well and it's
also got plenty of selenium and zinc
which has links to like healthy
testosterone production both men and
women want that and these ingredients
here yeah like the zinc the selenium the
vitamin D and also the bar and to an
extent do have interesting links there
as well so transparent Labs multivitamin
uh yeah we think this is the best for
women athletes before we go on I should
probably mention I know that this is
like a lot of information that we're
throwing you so if you would rather take
this information at your own pace we
have an article like version of this
video as well so if you want you can
just go to Google and write it in bar
Ben best women's multivitamins there's
cycle will come right up for now let's
move on to the next pick another
question we get a lot is what the best
multivitamin is for women 50 plus for
that we're going with rituals essential
for women over 50 plus uh ritual is a
really interesting company they have a
sort of minimalistic might be the wrong
way to hit but they try to not include
nutrients that you don't need and really
emphasize ones you do in extra
absorbable forms so this one does have
plenty of interesting ones for bone
health like vitamin D and K2 as
mentioned earlier those are pretty
strong links to bone health there's also
magnesium there for a bit of sleep
quality which something that people tend
to struggle with more as they age and on
top of that what I really like about
this in addition to all the B vitamins
it has as well for helpful energy
production is that one common problem as
people age is that they tend to it tends
to be harder to absorb nutrients like
the absorbed they tend to need more of
certain vitamins because they absorb
them less effectively just as a side
effect of Aging what ritual has done is
that it encases this nutrients in a
stomach acid resistant capsule it's
vegetarian in but what that means is it
should the goal for it is to pass
through the stomach not broken down so
that it breaks down in the digestive
tract in the intestines where it may
absorb more effectively so there's some
evidence to suggest that the body will
absorb these nutures more effectively if
it's further down a digestive tract like
in the larger the small intestine and
that's how this is made so it helps to
address common concerns about bone
health about sleep about heart health
and also about nutrient absorption and
all these are particularly important for
women 50 plus lastly what's interesting
like this is that rituals multivitamin
contains omega-3 fatty acids which
you've probably heard of as a supplement
but it's not usually included in
multivitamins because it's it's fat
right it's hard to take those stick
those in these like new nice dry
capsules so the way the capsule is made
is that you can see here it has a
combination of like a fatty component
and also some capsules in there as well
so basically this manages to include
omega-3 fatty acids into the formula in
a way that most competitors don't and
that has some pretty interesting
implications for among other things
inflammation and also bone health so
there really are a lot of ways that this
can potentially improve health in older
women especially with regard to immunity
inflammation bone health sleep and
nutrient absorption so uh really it's a
very solid product in Swift checking out
next up we've got a really interesting
category in the world of supplements
which is the best greens powder for that
one we're going with ag1 from athletic
greens this is a really really high
quality product there's a bit of a
primer on this one greens powders or
green superfood powder as they're often
called the idea with them is to provide
more than vitamins and minerals so
that's what you get in the multivitamin
the thing with greens powders like this
one is that they provide other
ingredients that are potentially
healthful we mentioned this a little bit
earlier ingredients like antioxidants
phytonutrients the digestive enzymes
probiotic bacteria adaptogens so in this
what's interesting is that you're still
getting plenty of vitamins and minerals
a lot of greens powders don't they'll
just focus on the antioxidants and stuff
but ag-1 does have plenty of like
vitamins a c e thiamine riber Flavin
biotin as well which is again often
requested by female customers zinc
selenium copper it really is a good
source of vitamins and minerals however
it also has several categories in there
providing the antioxidants since the
phytonutrients of someone so it's a
whole lot of Spirulina which is a very
very common supplement just on its own
you've got herbs and antioxidants you
got some CoQ10 which might have
important implications for heart health
you get digestive enzymes and even the
adaptogens as well so several kinds of
mushrooms and astragalus which as I
mentioned earlier adapters may help the
body to manage and respond to stress age
one is a really top quality product it
tastes pretty good as well a lot of
these cookies powders just they taste
like dirt maybe like dirt with a bit of
cocoa in it this is like a really
Pleasant like slightly tropical kind of
flavor because it's like papaya and
mango in there just a little bit so I
think it tastes really good and we also
think it's the best multivitamin for
women with probiotics as well because
that's a category that is really gets a
lot of attention these days there's more
and more research coming out that your
probiotic bacteria population like
that's the healthful bacteria that live
in your digestive tract that help you to
break down food and absorb nutrients
there's more and more evidence that they
could potentially have like play roles
in your overall inflammation level your
immunity as well in addition to possibly
even your mental health and stress
response that kind of stuff probiotic
bacteria is something that's of
increasing importance to a lot of folks
they want to get more of that in their
diet and ag-1 contains 7.2 billion of
them per serving and they're from two
different families as well because the
diversity of your microbiome is also
very important in addition to just like
how many bacteria you have down there
you also want to have a diverse
population so you've got 7.2 billion of
them here which is a lot and also
they're from two different families so
that's why eg1 is our favorite
multivitamin with probiotic bacteria
another area we really want to address
is transparency in multivitamins there's
nothing more frustrating than a product
that has interesting ingredients but
doesn't tell you how much of them it
contains that's why I like products like
how her which we name the most
transparent multivitamin so in addition
into having the precise the weights and
the precise percentage of the
recommended daily intake of all of the
ingredients here you can also go on
power's website and they will tell you
why they included these ingredients and
why they use that dosage as well on top
of that it all made in FDA registered
facility so you can be confident in like
the cleanliness safety and efficacy of
the product and it's also vegetarian
friendly so there's a lot going on with
power and yeah there are a lot of
reasons why we decided this was the best
transparent multivitamin for women
there's another very interesting area of
the industry called the individualized
approach right so the best
individualized women's multivitamins for
us is nourish so what does that mean
well some people they'll hear stuff like
this and they'll think it might sound a
bit scatter shot right like every single
person gets the exact same dosage of the
same vitamins but everyone's different
right you have different diets different
Lifestyles different needs different
ages so what's really cool about
companies like nourish is they'll give
you the nutrients that they think you
need and nothing that you don't so
basically you go to the website and you
a lot of quiz and it'll have a really
wide variety of questions and then
they're going to come to you and they'll
send you a box of your own
individualized multivitamins so if
you're a vegetarian you'll probably get
recommended some iron supplements
whereas if you eat meat every day you
probably won't need that and so on and
so on and so on the cost is generally
between 30 and 50 dollars per month and
when they give you recommendations on
their site you can add and subtract
based on what fits best within your
budget in addition to with your
lifestyle so definitely individualized
nutrition is a really cool area of
industry and nourishes the ones that are
doing it best the way that I like to
take my vitamins is in a gummy because
who doesn't want an excuse to eat some
candy and you might be the same and the
best Women's Multivitamin is definitely
smarty pants organic women's
multivitamins what's really cool at
these is well they're delicious and you
get a serving of four so you get to eat
four gummies every day you're welcome
but on top of that because of the
texture and consistency of the gummies
they're able to fit in some other
interesting ingredients so for instance
this one has omega-3 fatty acids in it
which you probably know I have
interesting links to immunity
inflammation and all sorts of things
like that but the product still manages
to be vegetarian which is Quite a feat
because a usually you get the Jelly like
consistency through gelatin and B
usually omega-3 fatty acids come from
fish but these ones come from flax seeds
so you get the benefits of omega-3 fatty
acids but you get them in a vegan form
the tasty and on top of all that it's
completely 100 organic as well so it's
organic it's vegetarian it's delicious
and you get things like Biotin and zinc
and selenium and other nutrients that
women tend to want in the multivitamins
as well so yeah I'm a big fan of gummies
and uh yeah smarty pants they act the
best in the market lastly we want to
touch on a good multivitamin for energy
a lot of people when they want to
multivitamin when they want some
supplements what they really want is to
have more energy throughout the day so
Legion Triumph is our favorite here it's
great as an all-rounder in the first
place like it's got plenty of the normal
ingredients like folate and biotin
magnesium that sort of stuff there's
also got a whole Suite of B vitamins
which as we mentioned if you're low in
them they could help to optimize energy
production there's also got some other
ingredients with interesting links to
energy like CoQ10 which may help to
Boost energy production in your body's
cells and then in addition to these
ingredients that are linked to energy
production there are also quite a few
ingredients linked to female sexual
health so you've got Tribulus terrestris
here which has some links to improving
female sexual well-being there's maca
root for libido and there's even chaste
Berry which has some potential links to
reducing side effects associated with
menstruation like cramps and headaches
and that sort of stuff so Legion Triumph
it's a pretty great pick for anything
but for energy production in particular
it's worth taking a look at all right
that does it for our pretty exhaustive
list of the best multivitamins for women
we did a lot of homework to land on that
list three really important areas that
we looked at when deciding on the ideal
multivitamins like one is the diversity
of ingredients ideally we're getting
vitamins and minerals but also other
ingredients outside of those we've
mentioned a few times the stuff you'll
find in Greens powders probiotic
supplements omega-3 fatty acids all
these sorts of things those really help
to round out a supplement in addition to
the best in ingredients the potentium
ingredients as well a good example is
Vitamin C if you have like just a little
bit of fruit or veggies throughout the
day it's very unlikely that you need to
supplement vitamin C at all if you have
a supplement that has 10 000 daily
vitamin C it looks impressive but it's
actually not very useful for the average
person so we prefer supplements that
focus on ingredients that people tend to
run a little bit low in stuff like
vitamin D magnesium that kind of thing
so both the diversity of ingredients and
also the potency of ingredients and
lastly the interaction of the
ingredients as well you don't want to
have every single vitamin every single
mineral all of them at 100 of the
rectangular intake in every single
supplement the reason that we absorb
things differently calcium for example
you are not going to absorb more than 50
of the recommend daily intake in one go
so you don't actually want a supplement
that's going to give you 100 of it you
can you're just gonna not absorb half of
it so it's kind of a waste of money in
that regard a lot of research a lot of
Publications like the Journal of the
American College of nutrition found that
too much zinc in the multivitamin can
lower the absorption of calcium so
that's why you don't actually have too
much zinc if calcium is really really
important to you or perhaps if you do
have zinc in there you do want extra
calcium because that's going to inhibit
the absorption as well so these are all
factors that come into play here when
you're picking a great multivitamin it
can be a bit of a headache to be mindful
of all these at the same time but you
know what that's what we're here for we
did all the homework and these are the
best multivitamins for women that we
landed on if you want to see the full
complete list remember you can just
Google bar Ben best multivitamins for
women and otherwise we hope you enjoyed
this video stick around get more coming
up